trademe.co.nz 2009-02-18

# TradeMe - New Zealand Online Auctions and Classifieds

Trade Me has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. This document discloses our information gathering and usage practices. For additional information about Trade Me, please review our  Terms and Conditions. 

**Use of your information**  
Trade Me **does not** sell or rent your personal information to third parties. 

We release account and other personal information only when we believe release is appropriate for legal compliance and law enforcement (including to government agencies with statutory law enforcement responsibilities); to facilitate court proceedings; enforce or apply our terms and conditions; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Trade Me Limited, our users, or others. Government agencies with statutory roles enabling them to request data from us includes but is not restricted to Police, IRD and the Ministry Of Economic Development. Members can contact Trade Me to ask whether such information has been provided. 

If you wish to take Dispute Tribunal proceedings against another member, you can contact Trade Me or the Disputes Tribunal for a statutory declaration, requesting contact details for the sole purpose of making a claim. 

**Email**  
It is the policy of Trade Me to send our members email throughout the auction process and other email they elect to receive, in addition to customary business communications (payment confirmations, etc.). Further, it is our policy to immediately remove any member from any mailing list upon the member's request. In addition, Trade Me will send newsletters and other communications to members. Newsletters will contain clear and obvious instructions for how the member can remove himself or herself from that mailing list. 

We do use email as a means of receiving feedback from our members, and we encourage you to email us with your questions or comments. 

**Emailing Tools**  
Trade Me provides facilities throughout the site to refer a friend to Trade Me or to send references to a specific listing to a friend. You may not use the "Email This Auction to a Friend" service or other email forwarding services that we offer to send spam or otherwise send content that would violate our privacy policy or Terms and Conditions. We do not permanently store, sell, or rent these email messages or the email addresses. 

**Membership Registration**  
Our site's registration form requires you to provide us contact information and may also require demographic information. We may use your contact information from the registration form to send you information about our company and promotional material from some of our affiliated partners. Your contact information is also used to contact you when necessary. 

**Updating Your Personal Information**  
Trade Me provides you with ways in which you can alter your personal data, including changing your email address, password, phone number, etc. Trade Me will store previous email addresses against your profile to ensure compliance with our Terms and Conditions \- specifically the use of one account per member. 

**Delivery Address Details**  
Trade Me enables you to save one or more of your delivery addresses which we will store against your profile. When you buy an item you have the option of selecting a delivery address which we will then send to the seller. We will never give the seller your address without your permission. 

**Payment Instructions Setup**  
Trade Me enables you to save and send a standard payment instructions email to the successful buyer when your auction ends. When you set up each auction you can choose to have the saved message sent automatically or edit your message at that time. 

**Control of Your Password**  
You are responsible for all actions taken with your user name, email address and password, including fees. Therefore we do not recommend that you disclose your Trade Me password to any third parties. If you choose to share your user name, email address and password or your information with third parties to provide you additional services, you are responsible for all actions taken with this information and therefore you should review that third party's privacy policy. 

**Credit Card Security**  
We work diligently to protect the security of your personal information, including credit card information. 

We protect your credit card information during transmission by using the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol, which encrypts your information when transmitted over the Internet. Trade Me retains only partial card details. However they may be held by either Direct Payment Solutions (DPS) (review their Privacy Policy) or Paystation ([ review their Privacy Policy](http://www.paystation.co.nz/cms_display.php?sn=17&st=1)) depending on which provider processes the transaction. 

When topping up your Trade Me account by credit card, you may have the option to "save this card for next time". If you choose this option, your credit card details are encrypted and securely stored by DPS. 

It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Ensure you logout when you have finished visiting Trade Me, especially if you access Trade Me from a shared computer. 

**Job applications**  
The "Apply Online" feature enables you to send a job application to organisations advertising on Trade Me Jobs. We forward these applications directly to the organisation listing the job and they are stored on our servers for a short time. We do not read these applications. 

**Cookies**  
Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored in a browser-related file on your computer's hard drive when you use our Web site. We use cookies to improve the member experience. We also use them to deliver information and fresh content specific to your interests. Cookies are widely used on most major Web sites. 

Trade Me mostly uses "session" cookies, which are removed from your computer once you leave Trade Me. These are used so our service can remember that you have logged in already and prevent you doing so more frequently. The technology we use (Microsoft Active Server Pages), requires the use of session cookies. Session cookies expire and are deleted after 30 minutes of no activity on Trade Me. 

Trade Me also uses persistent cookies to personalise the user experience, to help protect our members and to provide us with research information (such as how often members visit Trade Me each month). Persistent cookies allow us to track users on Trade Me and helps us identify users abusing the Trade Me service. 

Trade Me participates in Google's AdWords pay-per-click advertising programme. AdWords advertisements appear on Google's search result pages and on the Google Network. Google uses cookies to measure the number of Google users that click on an advertisement and visit certain Trade Me web pages, or who complete certain actions on the Website (such as adding an item to their Watchlist). Google provides this data to Trade Me without identifying the users. [View Google's privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html). 

**Other information we collect**  
We use additional information to do internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behaviour to better understand and serve you and our community. This information may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our site or not), which URL you next go to (whether this URL is on our site or not), what browser you are using, and your IP address. 

Users who login have their IP addresses recorded. This information will only be provided to legal authorities in cases of suspected fraud or for law enforcement purposes. This information is stored securely and will not be provided to other members or non-authorised parties. 

If you choose to post messages in our message areas or leave feedback for other users, we will collect that information you provide to us. 

If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Site, we may collect such information into a file specific to you. 

**Membership Removal**  
If you wish to have your registration removed from our directory for any reason, you may send us an email requesting this. 

**Advertising and Third Party Links**  
Some Trade Me advertisers may request information directly from users, or link to sites that do so. Trade Me has no control over its advertisers' privacy policies, and encourages users to review such policies prior to submitting any personal information to them. 

Trade Me contains non-advertising links to a variety of third party sites to enhance the member experience. Trade Me has no control of either the content or privacy policies of such sites, nor should such links be considered an endorsement of these sites except where otherwise noted. 

**Nielsen//NetRatings - NZ internet statistics**  
Trade Me, like most large New Zealand websites, uses the Nielsen//NetRatings counting system to collect information such as the number of visitors per day or the number of pages requested per day. To do this, Trade Me has a small piece of code on each page which counts these statistics. This enables us to see where we are in the 'top 10' list of New Zealand websites. 

For more information,  View the Nielsen//NetRatings privacy policy. 

**Updates to our information practices**  
From time to time, we make changes to our information practices or alter the functionality of our Web site. We always update this statement accordingly, so we encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on privacy practices at Trade Me. 

If you have any questions about our privacy policies or any other matter, please contact us.
